Exercise 1-15 Inflection Notice how the meaning changes while the actual words
stay the same. 1. I didn't say he stole the money. Someone else said it. 2. I
didn't say he stole the money. That's not true at all. 3. I didn't say he stole the
money. I only suggested the possibility. 4. I didn't say he stole the money. I
think someone else took it. Five. I didn't say he stole the money. Maybe he just
borrowed it. Six. I didn't say he stole the money, but rather some other money.
Seven. I didn't say he stole the money. He may have taken some jewelry. I didn't say
he stole the money. Someone else said it. It's true that somebody said it, but I
wasn't that person. I didn't say he stole the money. That's not true at all. Someone
has accused me, and I'm protesting my innocence. I didn't say he stole the
money. I only suggested the possibility. Maybe I hinted it. Maybe I wrote it in
some way I indicated that he stole the money, but I didn't say it. I didn't say
he stole the money I think someone else took it. I think someone stole the money
only not the person you suspect did it I didn't say he stole the money. Maybe he
just borrowed it I agree that he took it, but I think his motive was different I
didn't say he stole the money, but rather some other money we agree that he stole
some money but I don't think it's this money. I didn't say he stole the money. He
may have taken some jewelry. We agree that he's a thief, but we think he stole
different things. Notice that in the first half of these sentences, nothing changes
but the intonation.